all right well one stock we are watching
is the Canadian Insurance giant manual
Life Financial the stock is off to a hot
start this year it's outpacing the S&P
by a wide margin and here now to talk
about the landscape for the insurance
Market I'm pleased to say we have Roy
gory he is Manu life presid and CEO
joining us for an exclusive conversation
so I'm looking through the notes and you
have been calling this a transformation
2023 a transformational year your stock
is at the highest level since about 2008
is it still a transformation it is still
a transformation firstly it's great to
be here with you Katie um and you know
for our company we've been on a journey
of transformation since 2017 we said we
wanted to be the most Digital customer
Centric company in our industry but at
the same time we knew we had to drisk
our business and improve our returns
over the last 6 years we've increased
our return on Equity from from about 11%
to 16% we've divested a lot of low Roe
businesses and we've also digitized our
franchise so we're really pleased with
the progress that we've made and 23 was
certainly a milestone year for us uh we
achieved great operating results our
core earnings per share grew by 177%
double digit growth in our sales metrics
and we delivered positive net flows from
our wealth and asset management
franchise q1 was a nice momentum follow
on from Q from
2023 but you're right you know I think
organizations like ours don't ever stop
transforming I think as I look to the
decade ahead there's still a lot of
opportunity for us and we need to
continue to look for ways to Advance our
agenda and deliver great value for not
just customers but also for shareholders
well let's get into some of that
particularly in reinsurance so you've
done several deals over the past couple
months but just to set the scene the way
I think about reinsurance is basically
insurance for insurance companies is
that a fair description I think that's
right so insurance companies will reduce
their Risk by either reinsuring them or
or divesting blocks and again for us a
big priority for us over the last 6
years has been re insurance or
divestures we freed up $ 11 billion
worth of capital which has been a a key
part of how we've actually improved our
return on equity and reduced our risk
profile and we work with partners that
either take the business off our books
or who reinsure the business and
basically take on the risk associated
with it well you've been particularly
active when it comes to long-term care
actually it looks like you've reduced
your exposure to long-term care uh and
variable annuities through reinsurance
to 11% from 24% from 2017 which is also
the year that you took over as CEO do
you think that there's more deals there
are you going to pursue more long-term
care reinsurance deals to further exit
that business yes is the short answer in
23 we did a milestone historic long-term
care deal there weren't many deals ever
done before our transaction uh and it
was the largest ever in history so it
was an important signal to the market
that long-term care is transactable and
for us to be to have been being able to
trade the book pretty close to our book
value sent a really positive message to
the market and as a result of that there
are now many more interested parties who
are coming to talk to us about other
parts of our long-term care portfolio
that they may want to acquire or or take
on from us so so we think it was a good
first step we traded at a really very
attractive price but we think that
there's further opportunity so inbound
offers you're receiving you're not just
soliciting bids so to speak yeah so
there are people that are or companies
that are interested in talking to us
about our long-term care portfolio and
we're certainly engaging in
conversations with them so if you're
exposure is about 11% right now do you
have a specific Target in mind for where
you'd like to get to we wanted to get
our long-term care and variable annuity
which were the more problematic parts of
our
portfolio uh significantly reduced and
as you rightly point out they
represented about 24 24% of our earnings
in 2017 and now down to approximately 11
% we think a as we naturally grow our
business that percentage will continue
to decrease but if we can transact then
that will be a quicker way for us to
actually get down to certainly less than
10% so that's the state of reinsurance
and long-term care let's also talk about
Asia because you think about your recent
earnings report I think a lot of uh the
street was pleasantly surprised by the
growth in Asia Bloomberg intelligence
actually expects that uh the Region's
profit contribution could be 50% by 2027
how do you expand distribution in Asia
what does that look like yeah well we're
really proud of our Asia franchise it's
one of the things that really
differentiates us from our peers we've
got such a strong presence in Asia that
complements our North America
capabilities both in Canada and in the
US and again having a diversified
business across three broad geographies
is a significant Advantage certainly in
an environment where we're seeing GDP
growth in North America slow a little
bit and Asia continue to grow at 4 to 5%
we were the sixth largest Pan Asian
player many years ago and now we're a
top three player and you need to be a
top three player to grow and to have
credibility in that part of the world
now we've been in Asia for more than 125
years so we've got a strong brand and
presence there we've got a strong
distribution capability with about
100,000 agents but also 10 Bank
Assurance partners that we work with to
sell our insurance products so for Us
distribution is really key presence and
a brand also matters but we're very
optimistic about the outlook for our
business in Asia I have to say Bank
Assurance was a new vocab word for me as
I Was preparing for this interview uh
but before I let you go I do want to
talk about wealth and asset management
obviously an area of focus for you I
know you recently closed a deal to
acquire cqs and I'm wondering when you
think about growing that side of the
business are you trying to do that
through more Acquisitions or through
organic growth yeah that's a great
question our wealth and asset management
business has been a really big priority
and focus for us again we're quite
unique in that we're geographically
diverse um but we're also business
diverse in that we're not just a retail
shop we have an Institutional capability
but we also have a retirement capability
and with a world where the population is
constantly aging and there is a huge
retirement Gap that really positions us
really very well to capture business
growth and and momentum um so for us
growth will happen organically because
we're in parts of the world where our
products are in huge demand and need but
there's also an opportunity to put our
Capital to work and we're very well
capitalized so the investing in
businesses like cqs that add to our
capabilities is another way that we're
going to grow Beyond The Organic
opportunity that we've got well given
the share performance it seems like you
certainly have some money to spend uh
but Roy unfortunately we have to leave
it there hope to see you again soon our
thanks of course to ro gory of manual
life